Finding Aid for the J. Warren Perry Lyric Opera Papers and Music-Related Clippings, circa 1955-1997
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
J. Warren Perry Lyric Opera Papers and Music-Related Clippings, circa 1955-1997
Mus. Arc. 3.5
Perry, J. Warren
1 box (55 folders)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library 112 Baird Hall Buffalo, New York 14260-4750 United States Phone: 716 645-2924 Fax: 716 645-3906
Collection contains 6 folders of papers related to Perry's association with the Chicago Lyric Opera and 48 folders of clippings he compiled about vocalists, instrumentalists, conductors, and music halls.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dr. J. Warren Perry, 2004.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Dr. J. Warren Perry was born in Richmond, Indiana in 1921. He earned his B.A. at DePauw University in 1944, his Master's at Northwestern University in 1952, and his Ph.D. at Northwestern in 1955. Dr. Perry has been on the faculties at the University of Illinois at Chicago, Northwestern Medical School, and the University of Chicago. He was also employed as deputy assistant commissioner for research and training in the Vocational Rehabilitation Administration at the Department of Health, Education and Welfare in Washington, D.C. Dr. Perry is the founder of the School of Health Related Professions (now the School of Public Health and Health Professions) at the University at Buffalo, The State University of New York. He served as dean of the school from its founding in 1967 until 1977.
Dr. Perry devoted much of his life to supporting the arts. Before moving to Buffalo he was one of the founders of the Lyric Opera Company in Chicago. Since arriving in Buffalo Dr. Perry has served as chairman or board member for several local organizations, including the Buffalo Philharmonic, Community Music School, Theodore Roosevelt Inaugural National Historic Site, Artpark, and Friends of the Center for the Arts. The numerous awards granted to honor Dr. Perry's contributions to the community include the Buffalo Arts Councils' Supporter of the Arts award, the Buffalo Distinguished Citizen Award, and national Outstanding Philanthropist Award. Dr. Perry died August 5, 2010 in Buffalo.
J. Warren Perry was an avid collector of photographs and other artifacts related to music, especially opera and ballet. He worked for the Lyric Opera in Chicago as Director of the Committee on Education.
Scope and Content Note
Collection contains 6 folders of papers related to Perry's association with the Chicago Lyric Opera and 48 folders of clippings he compiled about vocalists, instrumentalists, conductors, and music halls.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
I. Lyric Opera papers
II. Subject files
Container List
- Lyric Opera Papers, circa 1955-1981, I.; Folder 1-6
  Arranged by subject subdivisions.
  - Lyric Opera clippings, 1955-1981, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lyric Opera Committee on Education, 1957-1960, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lyric Opera Correspondence, 1957-1961, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Correspondence to and from J. Warren Perry.
  - Lyric Opera lecture series, 1957-1960, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lyric Opera lecture series notes, 1957-1960, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes prepared for lectures by J. Warren Perry.
  - Lyric Opera publications, 1955-1960, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Subject files, 1957-1995, II.; Folder 7-XX
  Arranged alphabetically by subject into the following subseries:
  A. Ballet
  B. Buildings
  C. Conductors
  D. Instrumentalists
  E. Obituaries
  F. Operatic vocalists
  G. Musical cartoons
  - Ballet, 1954-1958, II.A; Folder 7
  - Buildings, undated, II.B; Folder 8-9
    - Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.), 1966, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Articles about transition from old to new building.
    - Multiple buildings, 1955-1960, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conductors, 1955-1967, II.C; Folder 10-20
    Alphabetically arranged by surname.
    - Beecham, Thomas, undated, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bernstein, Leonard, 1957, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Cleva, Fausto, undated, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Karajan, Herbert von, 1961, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Krips, Josef, undated, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Reiner, Fritz, undated, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Serafin, Tulio, undated, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Stravinsky, Igor, 1957, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Thomas, Theodore, 1955, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Toscanini, Arturo, 1957, 1967, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Walter, Bruno, 1956, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Instrumentalists, 1956-1978, II.D; Folder 21-28
    - Casals, Pablo 1956-1971, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Cliburn, Van, 1958-1959, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Ganz, Rudolph, 1966, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Horowitz, Vladimir, circa 1963-1978, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Kreisler, Fritz, 1967, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Rubinstein, Artur, 1956-1958, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Schweitzer, Albert, 1957, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Segovia, Andrés, 1959, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Obituaries, 1956-1997, II.E; Folder 29-41
    - Anderson, Marian, 1993, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - B, 1960-1997, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Cantelli, Guido, 1956, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - F, 1962-1981, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - G, 1956-1963, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - H-L, 1959-1976, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - M, 1960-1964, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - P, 1957-1960, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - R, 1958-1963, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - S, 1957-1965, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - T, 1957-1960, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Toscanini, Arturo, 1957, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - V-W, 1957-1984, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Operatic vocalists, 1956-1994, II.F; Folder 42-54
    - General articles about multiple vocalists, 1956-circa 1994, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - A-D, circa 1960-1982, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - F-G, circa 1956-1958, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - London, George, undated, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Lehmann, Lotte, 1968, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - M, 1960-1961, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Nilsson, Birgit, 1959-1961, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Price, Leontyne, 1960-1961, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - R, undated, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - S, undated, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Simionato, Giulietta, undated, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - T, 1957-1958, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - V-W, undated, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Musical cartoons, undated, II.G; Folder 55
    Musical cartoons from the popular press, including comic strips such as Peanuts and The Girls.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Lyric Opera of Chicago; Musicians--20th century; Musicians--Caricatures and cartoons
Genres
clippings (information artifacts); Cartoons
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
J. Warren Perry Collection of Photographs, ca. 1910-1971
Mus. Arc. 3.1
A collection of 2110 photographs, chiefly of opera singers and productions, with additional photographs of conductors, performers, ensembles, and concert halls.